Guide to the Yale Student Scrapbook Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale student scrapbook collection
1824-1968
RU 138
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
48.58
(46 boxes)
The materials consist of scrapbooks created by and for Yale students documenting student life at Yale.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of scrapbooks created by and for Yale students documenting student life at Yale.
College students; Scrapbooks; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Students
- Scrapbooks of Arthur S. Barnes, circa 1892; Accession 19ND-A-351
  - Scrapbooks of Arthur S. Barnes, circa 1892 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of Frederic Auchincloss and Benjamin Sheldon Richards, circa 1871; Accession 19ND-A-352
  - Scrapbooks of Frederic Auchincloss and Benjamin Sheldon Richards, circa 1871 (Box 1)
- Diary and scrapbooks of Paul S. Phenix, circa 1915-1918; Accession 1983-A-109
  - Diary and scrapbooks of Paul S. Phenix, circa 1915-1918 (Box 1)
  - Diary and scrapbooks of Paul S. Phenix, circa 1915-1918 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook documenting Class of 1898 Sheffield Scientific School, Accession 1987-A-078; 0.5; (1 box)
  - Scrapbook (Box 1)
- Yale-In-Wales scrapbook material, 1968; Accession 1988-A-020; 1.75; (1 box)
  - Scrapbook material, 1968 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of Miss Jessie Corbet, Accession 1988-A-025; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Athletic and commencement programs and invitations, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Commencement activities programs and invitations, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Athletic and commencement programs and invitations, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks and printed matter of James Sheffield, 1883-1955; Accession 1990-A-115
  - Scrapbooks and printed matter of James Sheffield, 1883-1955 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook and printed matter of Arthur Howe, 1909-1915; Accession 1990-A-117
  - Scrapbook and printed matter of Arthur Howe, 1909-1915 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Russel, Theodore F, 1888-1905; Accession 1990-A-120
  - Scrapbook ofRussel, Theodore F, 1888-1905 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of George Farnam Brown, 1905-1909; Accession 1991-A-086
  - Scrapbooks of George Farnam Brown, 1905-1909 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Ralph B. Durell, 1907-1911; Accession 1991-A-122
  - Scrapbook of Ralph B. Durell, 1907-1911 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook material, 1862-1915; Accession 1993-A-039
  - Letters from Timothy Dwight (younger), 1880 April 15 (Box 1)
  - Tuition bills, 1862-1865 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of the Class of 1865, 1915 (Box 1)
  - Yale/Princeton baseball program, 1896 (Box 1)
  - Yale '96 Triennial Book, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Various Class of 1865 programs, kept as if it was a scrapbook (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of J. Barbee Robertson, 1919-1928; Accession 1993-A-040
  - Scrapbook of J. Barbee Robertson, 1919-1928 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of George P. Stimson, 1894-1898; Accession 1993-A-044
  - Scrapbook of George P. Stimson, 1894-1898 (Box 1)
- Ephemera,memorabilia, and reunion materials for the Class of 1878 saved by William Brown Glover, Accession 1993-A-066
  - College and graduation ephemera and memorabilia, and reunion materials for the Class of 1878 saved inscrapbook-like fashion by William Brown Glover (Box 6)
  - College and graduation ephemera and memorabilia, and reunion materials for the Class of 1878 saved inscrapbook-like fashion by William Brown Glover (Box 7)
- Scrapbook of B. Edwin Law, 1924; Accession 1994-A-067
  - Scrapbook of B. Edwin Law, 1924 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of D.S. Norton, 1900-1902; Accession 1994-A-116
  - Scrapbook of D.S. Norton, 1900-1902 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Giles P. Greene, Class of 1911, Accession 1994-A-134
  - Scrapbook of Giles P. Greene, Class of 1911 (Box 1)
- Francis Thibault Boyd's college photograph scrapbook, Accession 1995-A-070
  - Francis Thibault Boyd's college photograph scrapbook (Box 1)
- Wyllys Rosseter Betts family scrapbooks, circa 1894-1931 and a writing book of Mary W. Scoville, 1824; Accession 1996-A-024
  - Two Wyllys Rosseter Betts family scrapbooks, circa 1894-1931 (Box 4)
  - writing book of Mary W. Scoville, 1824
- Scrapbook of C. W. Goodrich, Class of 1886, Accession 1996-A-025
  - Scrapbook of C. W. Goodrich, Class of 1886 (Box 1)
- Photograph album of the Yale Campus, "College Views", by Lawrence Heyworth, Sr., circa 1890-1925; Accession 2000-A-011
  - Photograph album of the Yale Campus, "College Views", by Lawrence Heyworth, Sr., circa 1890-1925 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Henry Ling Taylor (Class of 1875), 1873-1880; Accession 2001-A-115
  - Scrapbook of Henry Ling Taylor, (Yale 1875), 1873-1880 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Dickinson W. Richards, 1876-1917; Accession 2003-A-095
  - Scrapbook of Dickinson W. Richards, 1876-1917 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of James McCrea, Class of 1895, and George Stimson, Class of 1934, featuring the YAMS, 1933-1934; Accession 2003-A-097
  - Student Scrapbook of James McCrea, Class of 1895, and George Stimson, Class of 1898, featuring the YAMS, 1933-1934 (Box 1–2)
- Scrapbook of Fred W. Mathews, Class of 1896, Accession 2004-A-088
  - Scrapbook of Fred W. Mathews, Class of 1896 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Harris D. Colt, Class of 1884, documenting student life, circa 1880-1884; Accession 2005-A-175
  - Scrapbook of Harris D. Colt, Class of 1884, documenting student life, circa 1880-1884 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks and photographs of Harold Whiteman, Jr., documenting Yale football, 1935-1941; Accession 2007-A-212
  - Scrapbooks and photographs of Harold Whiteman, Jr., documenting Yale football, 1935-1941 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of Walter S. Sanford, 1896-1900; Accession 2007-A-215
  - Scrapbooks of Walter S. Sanford, 1896-1900 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Joseph Morey, Class of 1899, 1895-1899; Accession 2008-A-096
  - Scrapbooks of Joseph Morey (Class of 1899), 1895-1899 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of George Lyle Kingsley documenting athletics at Yale, circa 1882-1886; Accession 2009-A-123
  - Scrapbook of George Lyle Kingsley (Class of 1886) documenting athletics at Yale, circa 1882-1886 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Edwin C. Northrup, Class of 1904, circa 1900-1904; Accession 2010-A-071; 1.75
  - Scrapbook, Circa 1900-1904 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Joseph A. Archibald, Class of 1888 Sheffield, 1884-1888; Accession 2010-A-088; 0.25
  - Scrapbook, 1884-1888 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Frederick Sheffield 1924 Yale rowing crew, 1921-1929; Accession 2011-A-044; 1
  - Scrapbook, 1921-1929 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Thomas Langdon Cheney, Class of 1901, 1897-1901; Accession 2012-A-018; 1
  - Scrapbook, 1897-1901 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Edward Welles Penfield, Sheffield Scientific School 1883, 1879-1883, undated; Accession 2012-A-030
  - Scrapbook of Edward Welles Penfield, Sheffield Scientific School 1883, 1879-1883 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Loose items that accompanied the scrapbook., 1879-1883, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
- Scrapbook of Robert Maxwell Ingham documenting the combined Yale-Harvard Track Team, 1931; Accession 2013-A-080
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Nancy Park, 2013
  - Scrapbook, 1931 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook documenting James Otis Rodgers, Class of 1898, 1894-1934; Accession 2015-A-054
  Biographical / Historical
  James Otis Rodgers, from Toledo, Ohio, attended Yale from 1894-1898. He was a member of both the crew and football teams, and coached both teams following graduation.
  The scrapbook was compiled by his daughter, Carolyn Hale Rodgers, a niece of Edith Hale Harkness.
  Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Willard Walker Brown, Jr., 2015. Mr. Brown received the scrapbook from his grandmother, Louise Harkness Ingalls, daughter of Edith Hale Harkness.
  - Scrapbook, 1894-1934 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook documenting Maurice "Red" Robert Brann, PhB 1915, Circa 1903-1967; Accession 2017-A-056
  - Scrapbook, Circa 1903-1968 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of William Bacon Bailey, Class of 1894, 1901-1946; Accession 2018-A-0063
  Scope and Contents
  Three scrapbooks documenting reunion activity and related events of the Yale College Class of 1894, of which Bailey was a member, as well as Bailey's professional life as an economist, professor, census worker, statistician, and employee at Travelers Insurance Companies.
  Gift of Bradford Gray, 2018.
  - Scrapbook, 1909-1913 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1905-1930 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1909-1946 (Box 3)
  - Material removed from scrapbooks, 1905-1946 (Box 4)
    Includes professional correspondence, newspaper clippings, material related to the Bailey family, drawings, and Yale ephemera.